# **TUAN NGUYEN**

E: nganhtuan63@gmail.com - M: 408-417-0710 - Anaheim, CA 92804 linkedin.com/in/nganhtuan63 | github.com/nganhtuan63

### **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

Passionate software developer with 7+ years of experience in web development. Possesses practical knowledge in system design and optimization for high-performance. Develops well both backend and frontend components with focus on reusable code and thoughtful user experience.

- Programming languages: Node.js, PHP, HTML/CSS/Javascript
- Databases and Search: MySQL, SQL Server, Redis, Elasticsearch
- Cloud Platform: Amazon Web Services EC2, VPC, ECS, Cloudformation, S3, Lambda, API Gateways, SNS
- Others: Nginx, Docker container, Vagrant, Ansible, RabbitMQ, Varnish, Centos & Ubuntu, Git, Json Web Token
- Open source contribution: GXC-CMS (Github, featured on Softpedia)

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **Full Stack Developer**

Sep 2015 - Dec 2015

**Company**: BoostCommerce (https://boostcommerce.net)

- Designed and developed "Infrastructure as code" for the system with AWS Cloudformation
- Managed and deployed microservices with AWS EC2 Container Service, Elastic Load Balancer, AWS Route53
  - Developed REST APIs standard for Product Filter & Search app
  - Implemented APIs with AWS Lambda in Node.js and Serverless Framework
- Analyzed and designed ElasticSearch indices to support product filter and search for multiple stores

### Senior Web Developer

Mar 2015 - Sep 2015

Company: Hoang Phuc International (<a href="https://hoangphucinternational.com">https://hoangphucinternational.com</a>)

- Improved current e-commerce system for high traffic peak during sale campaigns
- Analyzed and designed Elasticsearch index for flexible product catalog filter

**Technical Team Lead** 

Jan 2013 - Feb 2015

Company: Tuoi Tre Newspaper (http://tuoitre.vn)

- Implemented and scaled the in-house CMS system for high-traffic 2 million page views/day with frequent updated content.
- Improved dynamic publishing workflow and multi-channel publishing
- Managed software development team 10 members

### **Software Developer**

Mar 2010 - Dec 2012

Company: Tuoi Tre Newspaper (http://tuoitre.vn)

- Developed first version of in-house Content Management System (CMS) for new publishing strategies
- Developed features & supported deploying <u>Atex CMS</u> for English-version online newspaper

## **Backend Web Developer**

Jul 2009 - Oct 2009

**Company**: Pyramid Consulting (<a href="http://www.pycogroup.com">http://www.pycogroup.com</a>)

- Implemented server-side features for web applications with PHP Zend Framework, MySQL, Memcache

## Frontend Web Developer

Sep 2008 - Jul 2009

**Company**: Vinasource (http://www.vinasource.com)

- Developed frontend with HTML/CSS/Javascript from PSD designs for .NET web applications.

### **EDUCATION**

Master's degree in Software Engineering

Jan 2016 - Dec 2017

California State University, Fullerton

**Bachelor of Science in Information System** 

Sep 2004 - Sep 2009

Ho Chi Minh City University of Science